ABHISHEK SHESHAGIRI

linkedin/abhishekds94 github/abhishekds94 www.abhishekds.site Email: abhishekds94@gmail.com

Mobile: +1(217)761-5585Springfield, IL,

USA. 62704

An experienced Android developer, Open for relocation anywhere in the USA

Summary

A self-directed and motivated Mobile Developer with a passion for creating beautiful UI, experimenting with patterns of the user experience through a mobile device to solve a real-time problem. Experienced in design and development with modern Android stacks like MVVM architecture, Live Data, REST APIs and Material Design

Work Experience

Information Technology Services

University of Illinois, Springfield

Graduate Student Assistant with Tuition Scholarship

August 2019 - Present

- o Mobile Development: Developing hybrid mobile apps in Flutter to make the campus go digital
- o Web Development: Developing web applications for the campus in Laravel PHP using Vue and Quasar frameworks

Radiant IT World

Shimoga, Karnataka, India

Mobile Applications developer - Best Employee, 2018

February 2018 - November 2018

- Worked on an image-based social-networking application where reduced the image fetch and upload time by nearly 60 percent by using Volley instead of Retrofit and Glide libraries
- Fixed a security breakout in less than 6 hours by releasing a patch that was optimized to check the image header before the media upload to prevent any injections and attacks to the server
- Developed two Hybrid mobile applications using React Native. Apps were developed for Android and iOS platforms with flex layouts and normal layouts and Worked on retrieving data from JSON response using REST APIs to parse it to UI modules. The apps were only 1.1 MB and 1.6 MB in size which increased its overall performance by 70 percent even on low latency (2G and 3G) networks

Pyplyn

Bangalore, India

Android Developer - Full Stack

July 2017 - January 2018

- Developed an Educational Android application using Java, PHP, MySQL, and Firebase with built-in Video players to stream the video tutorials. The application had around 800-900 daily users
- Worked on a Bank application in which the security features such as Fingerprint and OTP based login were implemented which increased the security of the application by 80 percent and used SQLite to store non-vital information which increased the application performance by 30 percent

Anugraha Computers

Shimoga, Karnataka, India August 2016 - April 2017

Android Developer

- City Center: Developed a parking ticket application for a popular shopping complex group. The application gave the slots to the customers as to where they could park their vehicles when they enter the parking area of the shopping complex. This was developed using Firebase as the service provider. The application was used in 35 shopping malls across the State and was generating around 300,000 tickets everyday
- o Yatra Cabs: Integrated an emergency services option in a popular taxi (ride-sharing) service application. The integration was about displaying the nearest hospital from the current location with Navigation and also an automated text message to the police control room about the start and the endpoints of the route. The integration was developed using Geo-fencing technology with volley services to send and receive requests and also Google Maps SDK to populate the navigation to the nearest Hospital
- Loki Mo-bikes: Developed an Admin application for a two-wheeler booking company. The app had various features to check the
 bookings that were done by the users based on different locations and dates. The application used a REST API to retrieve the
 response from the database that was provided by the client
- o **Truth or Dare**: Developed a Truth or Dare game using Firebase as back-end. The application allows players to play the truth or dare game for a maximum of 5 players at any given time

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Computer Science

Springfield, IL

University of Illinois at Springfield

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science

 $\begin{array}{c} May~2020\\ {\rm Shimoga,~Karnataka,~India} \end{array}$

Jawaharlal Nehru National College of Engineering

July 2017

Android Developer Nanodegree Program

Udacity.com

Online certification for Android developers with experience in developing mobile applications in Java

 $April\ 2020$

SKILLS

Take Me There!, An Android Application: (March 2020 - April 2020)

- An application that displays all the nearby restaurants using Zomato API from the User's current location and an option to navigate
 using google maps
- It contains details such as cost for two, user votes and ratings, images, directions
- · Users can also know more about the place that would take them to Zomato's landing page on click to know more about the place
- Under Settings, Users can set preferences such as distance, Cuisine Preference, Search Radius, and so on
- · Click here for the Github repository

Bakers Bowl, An Android Application: (February 2020 - March 2020)

- · An application for users to display various recipes with step-wise instructions using video tutorials
- Used REST API, Fragments and Exo-Player to develop this application
- Added a home screen widget function with an automated Espresso testing functionality to increase the effective performance of the application
- Click here for the Github repository

Movie Mania, An Android Application: (December 2019 - January 2020)

- An application for displaying details of various movies using The Movie Database API
- Used REST API, Intents, Picasso Library for image loading and Retrofit library to retrieve data from the API
- Application has sorting option based on Highest Rated, Popular Movies and Favorites Movies. All the favorite moveis are saved on the device using the Room Database with Live Data
- Click here for the Github repository

UIS Walking Routes, A Flutter based Hybrid Mobile Application: (November 2019 - December 2019)

- An application for users to check the Distance traveled, Calories burnt, and Time spent on walking routes in campus with live tracking
- Used Google Maps SDK, OpenWeather API and Email Client library for email feedback without server
- Click here for the Github repository

Motor Insurance Premium Calculator, An Android Application: (January 2018 - March 2018)

- An application developed using basic java concepts for calculating Motor Insurance Premium, it is now used across India by various Insurance companies
- The app has more than 50,000 downloads to-date
- Click here for the Github repository
- Click here for the Google play store listing

Smart Parent, A React Native Hybrid Mobile Application: (March 2017 - April 2017)

- An application that serves as a digital dashboard for Parents and the Teachers with a one-one chat window in all schools
- The application was built using PHP-MySQL as backend server to store the data along with Firebase for chat, notifications and authentication

Locatify, An Android Application: (February 2016)

- This application was developed for the Government of India under Make in India program to provide a manual green corridor for all the emergency vehicles in metropolitan cities
- The Application was developed using Geo-fencing technology with Google Maps SDK, Firebase Realtime database and Notifications
 with a provision to connect to any IoT devices to control the traffic signals
- This application was judged as the Most Popular Project in the hackathon by the Government of India